Guide to the Senior Honor Essays of Yale Students
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Alphabetical, Series I
  - Zlotkowski, Edward A.--Unity and Duality: A Study of Dylan Thomas' Poetic Development, 1966 (Box 46)
  - Author unknown--Title unknown (essay about Fitzgerald), undated (Box 46)
- Numerical, Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Note: folder column refers to essay number.
  - Senior Honor Essays
    - Goldberger, Paul J.—"Romantic Pragmatism: the Work of James Gamble Rogers at Yale University", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Lee, Carol F.—"The Structure of the New Haven County Legal Profession: 1780-1865. The Dark Ages Revisited", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Parker, Michael P.—"What a Thing is Man! A Study of Rochester's Social Satires", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ettinger, John R.—"The Structure of Political Parties in Vermont 1824-1840", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Thomas, Jonathan Y.—"'Down Under and Out Yonder' A Comparative Study of the Australian and American Frontiers", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Jones, Terri E.—"Undergraduate drama at Yale", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Jordan, Teresa—"Meanwhile back at the ranch: Wyoming ranchers during the Great Depression", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Abel, Bruce—"Survival and deterrence: a study of attitudes and theories concerning civil defense.", 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Abrams, Alan—"Southern attitudes toward foreign affairs", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Adams, John P.—"Three strings to the bow: a study of Great Britain and the political unification of Europe, 1945 - 1958", 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Adamu, Haroun-al-Rashid—"Makurdi: Half a century of crisis. An analysis of ethnic politics in a Nigerian town: 1918 - 1968", undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Alexander, Donald Crichton—"The Arkansas plantation, 1920 - 1942" (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Alper, William A.—"Generations and politics in Tanzania", 1969 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Bachelder, Joseph E., III—"Characteristics of contemporary public opinion and foreign policy", 1955 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Baker, Livingston—"Test of a new administration; a reconstruction of American foreign policy during the Indochina crisis of 1954", 1958 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Baker, Robert H.—"The tax decision process in Cleveland", 1965 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Ball, David George—"The use of pupil placement laws in the south as a device to avoid integration", 1960 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Banks, John R.—"The influence of political parties", 1959 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Barney, Albert W., Jr.—"Policies and pressures in a New England town, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Barr, Jerry Michel—"Pressure groups and legislative decision making Indiana, 1957", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Barrett, William L. D.—"The American Civil Liberties Union as a friend of the Supreme Court", 1960 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Bates, Richard E.—"The urban political machine", 1961 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Bates, Timothy—"How people use leaders", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Bedrick, Stephen B.—"The politics of urban redevelopment", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Berlstein, George—"Business affected with a public interest", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Bermann, George A.—"Escobedo and beyond: The Supreme Court, the right to counsel, and the states", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Bingham, Stephen M.—"A congressman's decision", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Blunt, William W., Jr.—"The Bricker Amendment: a study of a political philosophy and its application", 1958 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Boell, Carl D.—"Electronic politics: electing John Lindsay in 1969", 1970 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Bohling, A. L.—"A plan for the reorganization of the congressional committee system and for legislative-executive liaison", 1947 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Bolton, John Robert, II—"Cybernetics and Suez; a case study of decision making", 1970 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Brandon, Michael—"The political role of labor in the United States and in Great Britain", 1949 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Breimer, Bruce John—"The New York City Democratic reformers battle the "Bosses" and themselves", 1967 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Brokaw, John I.—"The origins of judicial review", 1952 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Brown, George A., Jr.—"The boss: a study of Jesse Unruh and machine politics", 1966 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Brunner, Ronald D.—"Communication and control in international politics. A case study of Nazi Germany", 1964 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Burnley, James H.—"The influence of the press on U.S. foreign policy toward Cuba in 1957-1958 and Vietnam in 1963", 1970 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Cahoon, John T., Jr.—"City councils: the forgotten branch; the case of the New Haven Board of Aldermen", 1968 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Camp, Thomas F.—"Civil rights legislation in the 86th Congress", 1961 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Caplan, Alan P.—"Canada: sovereign state or nation?", 1960 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Cascone, Kenneth T.—"Ghana: a study of its politics", 1962 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Cattier, Jean—"Belgian administration of the territory of Ruanda-Urundi under the League mandate system and the United Nations trusteeship", undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Chai-Onn, Arthur—"A research report on Singapore- her political development and political parties, the trade union movement, and her education system", 1956 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Chittenden, Thomas S.—"United Nations expanded program of technical assistance", 1957 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Coffin, William Sloane, Jr.—"Notes towards a history of Bolshevik trade unionism", 1949 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Coggins, Paul—"Justice inside the walls", 1973 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Collier, Earl M., Jr.—"Black political participation in Richmond, Virginia in the second reconstruction: analysis of a social movement", 1969 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Crosby, John—"The impact of Pakistan on the foreign policy of India", 1957 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Daniels, Douglas—"Negro voting behavior in Chicago, 1932-1956", 1958 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Davidson, Sidney W., Jr.—"The development and prospects of Labrador", 1943 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Davis, Edward W.—"An exact algorithm for the multiple constrained-resource project scheduling problem", 1968 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Davis, Muller—"The dissenting voices; a study of propaganda attacks on the United Nations", undated (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - DeForest, Stephen E.—"Some contemporary characteristics of American interest group elite opinion", 1955 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - de Raismes, Joseph N., III—"French administration and the Common Market", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Devine, Frank E.—"The India-Pakistan question; an evaluation of the role of the United Nations in the dispute between India and Pakistan over the State of Jammu and Kashmir", 1962 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Dieterly, Richard—"Merger in Middletown: a case study", 1956 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Dirickx, Yvo—"Dynamic programming models with discount factor greater than one", 1971 (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Doret, David M.—"Political conversation at Yale", 1968 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Dyer, Richard H.—"The quasi-judicial aspects of congressional investigation", 1953 (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Eecken, Jacques Vander—"Investigation of a class of constrained inventory problems", 1968 (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Elstein, Henry—"The McLevy complex: analysis of voting behavior in Bridgeport, Connecticut", 1956 (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Emmons, David—"The Fuehrerprinzip in national socialism", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Etheredge, Lloyd S.—"Hypnosis and order: the psychology of habitual compliance", undated (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Fletcher, Robert A.—"The Bremen Constitution: a case study in military government and German democracy, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Fox, Merritt B.—"An appraisal of proposals for revenue sharing in the United States", 1968 (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Furniss, Norman—"De-Stalinization and the French Communist Party", 1966 (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Garvin, Andrew P.—"The United States political communication effort in Vietnam: an operationalized fourth dimension", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - Godburn, Paul A.—"The fight for City Hall", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Gordon, Jeffrey N.—"A contradiction in foreign aid policy", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - Greenawalt, Kim C.—The vice-presidency: former depths and new heights", 1965 (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - Greenberg, Edward J.—"The sea of controversy", 1959 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - Haas, G. William—"Aspects of Nigerian nationalism: the action group party and the EGBE OMO ODUDUWA ", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - Hammett, Harold D—"Conventions, constitutions, and legislative power: the Texas experience, 1845-1960" (Box 12, Folder 73)
    - Handel, Thomas F.—"The airlines strike of 1966: the facts and the issues", 1970 (Box 13, Folder 74)
    - Harris, Jamie O.—"The Torrey Canyon Disaster; some legal considerations", 1968 (Box 13, Folder 75)
    - Harris, William R.—"The lost crusade; a study of Wendell Willkie and the Republican Party, 1938-1942", 1947 (Box 13, Folder 76)
    - Hart, Charles M.—"Attempts to amend the displaced persons act of 1948 in the 81st Congress (1948-1950)", 1959 (Box 13, Folder 77)
    - Hasbrouck, Sherman—"The politics of planning", 1950 (Box 13, Folder 78)
    - Hawkins, Richard H., III—"Latin America: the business of international relations", 1968 (Box 13, Folder 79)
    - Hawthorne, Hayden T., Jr.—"The new statesman and nation, 1945-1951; a cross-current in socialism", 1956 (Box 13, Folder 80)
    - Helm, T. Kennedy, III—"Strategies of influence in public education; a study of the Louisville Board of Education", 1968 (Box 13, Folder 81)
    - Helzer, James A.—"The Italo-Ethiopian crisis of 1934-1935 as a problem in American foreign affairs", 1968 (Box 14, Folder 82)
    - Hemphill, Robert F., Jr.—"The Korean minority in Japan", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 83)
    - Henton, Douglas—"The federal social policy system, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 84)
    - Herman, Richard A.—"The 1949 "Dixiegop" Coalition and its probable effect upon the senate elections in 1950" (Box 14, Folder 85)
    - Herman, Robert Thomas—"Congress and the consumer—and Ralph Nader", 1968 (Box 14, Folder 86)
    - Herr, Stanley—"Community action in the Negro neighborhood; the Clinton Hill findings", 1967 (Box 14, Folder 87)
    - Hess, Michael D.—"Political Succession: a struggle for Republican Party leadership in New York County, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 88)
    - Hillman, Richard A.—"Free speech; an ethical and political problem", 1959 (Box 15, Folder 89)
    - Holzer, Steve—"The Wallace phenomenon: conservative surge or populist resurrection?" 2 vols., 1970 (Box 15, Folder 90)
    - Howe, William—"Grover Cleveland and the presidency", undated (Box 15, Folder 91)
    - Hughes, Paul C.—"The relations between Mexico and the United States from the time of Diaz to the present day", 1939 (Box 15, Folder 92)
    - Hunt, Peter—"The progressives: their program and their ideas, 1900 to 1912", 1958 (Box 15, Folder 93)
    - Jedlicka, Frank E., Jr.—"Workers and Peasants ", 1953 (Box 15, Folder 94)
    - Jennings, Bruce—"Community action and social reform: an organizational perspective", 1971 (Box 16, Folder 95)
    - Johnson, George R.A.—"The island in the winds; the politics of nationalism in Madagascar", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 96)
    - Johnson, James F., 4th—"The nationalization of British and American oil properties in Ceylon, 1962", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 97)
    - Johnson, Richard—"The Communist Party and the French students; a study of ideology and action", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 98)
    - Jonsson, Olafur R.—"The Anglo-Icelandic fisheries dispute", 1960 (Box 16, Folder 99)
    - Joost, Robert H.—"Some contemporary characteristics of American newspaper opinion on foreign affairs", 1957 (Box 16, Folder 100)
    - Joseph, Frank E., Jr.—"The effect of the full faith and credit clause upon interstate relations", 1950 (Box 16, Folder 101)
    - Joyce, Walter E., Jr.—"The genesis of the new deal", 1947 (Box 16, Folder 102)
    - Jurvis, Lorin A.,—"Perón and his cross; a study of church-state relations during the Perón regime, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 103)
    - Kahn, Peter J.—"Talking 'Turkey' and acting 'Chicken'; Congress and the War Power, 1965-1972", 1973 (Box 17, Folder 104)
    - Kaiser, Robert G.—"America and the Congo: a case study of the conduct of United States foreign policy", 1964 (Box 17, Folder 105)
    - Kalymon, Basil A.—"Stochastic costs in multi period decision models", 1970 (Box 17, Folder 106)
    - Karas, Thomas H.—"The MLF: a case study in United States nuclear weapons control policy", 1966 (Box 17, Folder 107)
    - Katzman, Karan E.—"The administration and politics of community run neighborhood organizations", 1971 (Box 17, Folder 108)
    - Kaufmann, William W.—"Non-intervention in Spain, 1936-1939" (Box 17, Folder 109)
    - Kelley, James F.—"The presidency in Brazil; power and political influence", 1963 (Box 18, Folder 110)
    - Kennedy, C. B.—"The development of the Virginia charter from 1566 to 1609", 1943 (Box 18, Folder 111)
    - Kennedy, Roger G.—"The ethical development of Lawrence Dennis; the biography of a value-system", 1949 (Box 18, Folder 112)
    - Kirby, Peter—"Cognitive dissonance theory and the impact of the prayer cases: a critical review", 1971 (Box 18, Folder 113)
    - Knoble, Gary W.—"The historical trend of United States bilateral technical assistance", 1960 (Box 18, Folder 114)
    - Knull, William H., III—"The politics of land reform; a comparative study of Taiwan and the Philippines", undated (Box 18, Folder 115)
    - Koegler, Kurt—"The Anglo-Iranian oil dispute and its solution", 1962 (Box 18, Folder 116)
    - Kopman, C. E.—"Presidential initiative and influence in the legislative process", 1958 (Box 18, Folder 117)
    - Krieger, Joel—"Toward an explanation of the hegemony of Marxism in Russia", 1973 (Box 18, Folder 118)
    - Kyros, Peter N., Jr.—"Administrative assistants to members of Congress", 1970 (Box 19, Folder 119)
    - Ladd, A. H.—"Nationalism in Argentina; World War I to Perón", 1956 (Box 19, Folder 120)
    - Lamm, Robert P.—"The British police and the racial question", 1969 (Box 19, Folder 121)
    - Lamoree, Paul—"The political theories of Russell Kirk", 1964 (Box 19, Folder 122)
    - Lauritzen, A. R.—"Social change as a factor in the development of inter-party competition in the United States", 1964 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - Lawler, Richard R., Jr.—"Military assistance: problems and questions", 1967 (Box 19, Folder 124)
    - Lawler, Ross—"Government in the Fiji Islands", 1942 (Box 19, Folder 125)
    - Lee, George A., Jr.—"A study in democratic action", 1949 (Box 20, Folder 126)
    - Lee, Mark W.—"Police and politics: an analysis of the Knapp Commission", 1973 (Box 20, Folder 127)
    - Leich, John—"The practice of states as a formative element of international law", 1947 (Box 20, Folder 128)
    - Leka, Donald G.—"A reform movement in Oklahoma", 1964 (Box 20, Folder 129)
    - Levine, Paul Reed—"International executive agreements", 1942 (Box 20, Folder 130)
    - List, Lawrence—"Suicide pact? A study of the intention of the free speech clause of the First Amendment", 1958 (Box 20, Folder 131)
    - Little, Christopher M.—"Sweden and the common market", 1963 (Box 20, Folder 132)
    - Looper, Robert B.—"The Majoritarian attack on the constitution", 1949 (Box 20, Folder 133)
    - McComb, Donald P.—"France and European union", 1958 (Box 20, Folder 134)
    - Mack, Dennis W.—"Reform, participation, and political development", 1965 (Box 21, Folder 135)
    - Mandelbaum, Michael E.—"Political conservatism in Orange County, California", 1968 (Box 21, Folder 136)
    - Mann, Robert B.—"Avenues to alliance", 1968 (Box 21, Folder 137)
    - Marcus, George E.—"From proletarian to peasant; attitudes influencing economic decision-making in a Guyanese rice-farming village", 1968 (Box 21, Folder 138)
    - Mew, Calvin Marshall—"The French Communist Party: a study of existence", 1969 (Box 21, Folder 139)
    - Meyer, Frederick Robert—"Liberal and conservative in the ivy league", 1959 (Box 21, Folder 140)
    - Meyer, Russell W., Jr.—"Procedural reform of congressional investigations", 1954 (Box 22, Folder 141)
    - Miller, Peter P.—The Nuremberg trial and international law", 1960 (Box 22, Folder 142)
    - Moreno, Carlos R.—"Mexican American political behavior", 1970 (Box 22, Folder 143)
    - Murphy, Frederic H.—"Topics in nonlinear programming: penalty function and column generation algorithms", 1971 (Box 22, Folder 144)
    - Murphy, Irving Olds—"Congressional investigation of personal political beliefs", 1949 (Box 22, Folder 145)
    - Nakanishi, Don Toshiaki—"The visual panacea: an examination of the concept of general perceptions", 1971 (Box 22, Folder 146)
    - Nelson, C. William—"The impact of Cape Kennedy on Brevard County politics", 1965 (Box 23, Folder 147)
    - Neumann, Ronald M.—"The fire next time: the effect of task on organization and training in the New Haven Fire Department", 1973 (Box 23, Folder 148)
    - Nilsson, Claes M.—"A comparative study of neutralism", 1969 (Box 23, Folder 149)
    - O'Keefe, Kevin C.—"South Vietnam: rural pacification under the Diem Regime", 1968 (Box 23, Folder 150)
    - Olick, Arthur Seymour—"We hold these truths—", 1952 (Box 23, Folder 151)
    - Olmsted, Richard S.—"The abandonment of consolidation in New England", undated (Box 23, Folder 152)
    - Olsen, Donald J.—"Schism in the Americas; a survey of Argentine foreign policy 1939-1946", 1949 (Box 23, Folder 153)
    - Olson, William—"The electoral college and its critics", 1957 (Box 24, Folder 154)
    - Owen, Robert—"The political philosophy of Cecil Delisle Burns", 1941 (Box 24, Folder 155)
    - Padegs, Juris—"Societ policy and the unity of Germany", 1954 (Box 24, Folder 156)
    - Palmes, Robert Bruce—"Freedom of speech: the National Labor Relations Act and the Labor-Management Relations Act", 1948 (Box 24, Folder 157)
    - Parmer, Hugh Q.—"Political campaign; Fort Worth, Texas", 1960 (Box 24, Folder 158)
    - Payne, John M.—"Notes towards a study of power: seven approaches", 1963 (Box 24, Folder 159)
    - Penrod, Steven D.—"Party identification and political activism in Branford, Connecticut: a statistical study", 1969 (Box 24, Folder 160)
    - "Peronism", 1968 (Box 25, Folder 161)
    - Pfeffer, Richard M.—"The fluoridation problem", 1958 (Box 25, Folder 162)
    - Postol, Sidney S.—"Democracy and Marxism in Europe, 1840-1871", 1939 (Box 25, Folder 163)
    - Pressman, Jeffrey L.—"House vs. Senate: a study of conflict in the appropriations process", 1965 (Box 25, Folder 164)
    - Puchala, Donald—"A study in comparative colonial development", 1961 (Box 25, Folder 165)
    - Quinlan, Robert J.—"New England town meeting; pattern for democracy", 1952 (Box 25, Folder 166)
    - Rak, Daniel S.—"A study of the appeal of communism to the individual in the United States", 1954 (Box 25, Folder 167)
    - Reback, Gary L.—"The effects of precint-level voter contact activities on voting behavior", 1971 (Box 25, Folder 168)
    - Redman, M. C.—"Characteristics of New Haven Negro leaders", 1963 (Box 25, Folder 169)
    - Rettie, Dwight F.—"United States Reclamation Policy", 1952 (Box 26, Folder 170)
    - Rice, Sheldon M.—"Citizen participation in urban renewal", 1964 (Box 26, Folder 171)
    - Ridland, Rob—"Ear to the ground; administrative policy-making in the public interest", 1973 (Box 26, Folder 172)
    - Rinaldi, Charles F.—"Lenin's conception of the relationship between the party and the working class", 1957 (Box 26, Folder 173)
    - Riseling, Richard L.—"A strategy for disarmament", 1962 (Box 26, Folder 174)
    - Ritter, Alan—"The political thought and activity of Marcel Dóat (1930-1944)", 1958 (Box 26, Folder 175)
    - Robbins, Sabin, Jr.—"The plural society and Kenya", 1956 (Box 26, Folder 176)
    - Robson, Charles B. Jr.—"German foreign policy and the SPD: 1952-1959", 1961 (Box 26, Folder 177)
    - Rousselot, Peter F.—"The convergence of nationalism and communism in Cuba, 1959-1962", 1963 (Box 27, Folder 178)
    - "Saar Problem", undated (Box 27, Folder 179)
    - Schmid, A. E. S.—"The due process clause and state criminal procedure", 1950 (Box 27, Folder 180)
    - Schmidt, Byron Lee—"Victimless crimes: a case study of the criminal justice system of Kansas City, Missouri", 1973 (Box 27, Folder 181)
    - Schneider, Frederic T.—"The sugar bill of 1960; foreign policy and American politics", 1963 (Box 27, Folder 182)
    - Seed, Peter H.—"A case study of the Narrows Bridge Project", undated (Box 28, Folder 183)
    - Shapiro, Richard Edwin—"Citizens and city planning: a case study of Philadelphia", 1949 (Box 28, Folder 184)
    - Slaughter, Alexander—"Section 315 and the nation: a study of the implications of the priniciple of equal opportunities in political broadcasting", 1960 (Box 28, Folder 185)
    - Sleeper, James A.—"The New Jews: a study in youth ferment", 1969 (Box 28, Folder 186)
    - Snider, George R., Jr.—"The Kennedy buildup: a study of the role of the press in campaign politics", 1962 (Box 28, Folder 187)
    - Snyder, Frank G., Jr.—"The origins and growth of a nationalist party: implications for post-independence Mali", 1964 (Box 28, Folder 188)
    - Sommerville, W.D., Jr.—"The jurisdiction of the Freedmen's Bureau, 1865-1872", 1942 (Box 28, Folder 189)
    - Spalding, Charles C.—no title, Subject: the state of Hawaii, undated (Box 29, Folder 190)
    - Sprague, Peter J.—"The press under totalitarian regimes", 1961 (Box 29, Folder 191)
    - Stein, Robert S.—"The political origins and implications of student activism: with particular focus on television as a socializing factor", 1970 (Box 29, Folder 192)
    - Steiner, Erik Jay—"Social class and personality; an attempt at understanding certain relationships between the personality and the social system", 1967 (Box 29, Folder 193)
    - Steiner, Steven E.—"Campaign for the bench", 1963 (Box 29, Folder 194)
    - Stern, Jeffrey M.—"The psychology of politics: social cross pressures and attribution theory as signifiers of attitudes and behavior", 1970 (Box 30, Folder 195)
    - Stock, Arthur J.—"Senator Taft's foreign policy", 1954 (Box 30, Folder 196)
    - Stocker, Ken—"The national cancer attack act of 1971— the defeat of Laskerite control of government health policy", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 197)
    - Stone, Leonard Williams—"The town meeting form of government: Longmeadow, Massachusetts: a study", 1949 (Box 30, Folder 198)
    - Strohbehn, Edward Lynde, Jr.—"Political development of the Peace Corps.", 1962 (Box 30, Folder 199)
    - Stroock, Thomas Frank—"Cuba's constitutional problems; a study of the major issues joined in the Cuban Constitutional Convention of 1940", 1948 (Box 30, Folder 200)
    - Talmadge, Philip—"The Nixon doctrine and reactions to it by three Asian nations", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 201)
    - Taylor, Willard B.—"The French popular front", 1962 (Box 30, Folder 202)
    - Thomas, John Lowell—"Private enterprise in space; a legislative history of the communications satellite act of 1962", 1963 (Box 31, Folder 203)
    - Vance, Estil, Jr.—"Factional dualism in the Texas Democratic Party, 1936-1958", 1960 (Box 31, Folder 204)
    - Veselka, Larry—"The new economic globalism", 1973 (Box 31, Folder 205)
    - Wahi, Pran N.—Theory and computation of integer linear programs", 1969 (Box 31, Folder 206)
    - Wainwright, William R.—"A Prolegomenon to the postscript; France, or otherwise, 1968", 1970 (Box 31, Folder 207)
    - Wakefield, A.—"In search of a home: Quebec in the Canadian federal system", 1964 (Box 32, Folder 208)
    - Waldoks, Phillip H.—"Personality and Politics: a case study of David Ben Gurion", 1973 (Box 32, Folder 209)
    - Weinstein, Brian G.—"Arab unity; a study of transactions and communications", 1959 (Box 32, Folder 210)